[Genius Girlfriend]
[Episode 5]
I told myself,
it's great to have a rival.
Whether I win or lose,
all is fair and square.
But another voice in my heart
keeps asking.
It was you who held my hand
to escape the aquarium.
It was you who buried
the wish box with me.
If this isn't a friend,
then what should a friend be like?
Hey—
Lin Zhixia!
Why are you so absent-minded?
What's wrong?
The only person in our group
who can't have any problems
is you.
Otherwise, as someone
tagging along for the contest,
I won't be able to explain it to my mom.
I...
I have a friend.
Don't say "friend." I know.
Just say it's you.
I really have a friend.
He's quite nice to me,
and I've always treated him
as a good friend.
But recently I heard them say
that they only sees me as a rival
and wants to defeat me.
I've seen plenty of girls like this.
Don't take it to heart.
He's a boy.
A boy is acting like that too?
Lin Zhixia, I didn't know you well before.
I thought you
disdained hanging out
with us ordinary people.
But in this period of time,
I felt you're actually quite nice.
You just aren't good at
getting along with people.
Listen to me.
This friend is definitely jealous of you.
He treats me quite well.
Then...
did he ask you to tutor him
or ask what books you read
and what practice questions you do?
See, he's just using you.
That's why he treats you well.
Listen to me.
I'm very experienced in this.
But...
Fine,
if you don't believe me,
don't you believe books?
I remember a good quote from a book.
Time will filter out fake friends.
This friend of yours
is a fake friend filtered out by time.
Just ignore him.
Then I should just
give him the cold shoulder?
Time will give you the answer.
It's about time.
Let's go back and review.
I thought we were done for today.
Okay, let's do some practice.
[Constantly Strive to Become Stronger;
Strive to Be Number One]
Now, open your book.
Turn to page 27.
Comprehending:
one.
Read the passage carefully
and join the correct part
of the sentences.
Lin Zhixia.
You caused me to miss the contest.
But you prepared
quite well yourself, didn't you?
Wh-What do you want?
Nothing.
I'm free now anyway.
I have plenty of time.
You don't think you can just stick up
for Duan Qiyan
and then walk away, do you?
What are you doing?
If I see you approach Lin Zhixia again,
it won't be as simple as
withdrawing from the contest.
Do you want to be expelled?
Lin Zhixia,
I'll say it right here.
Tomorrow,
don't even think about
participating in the contest in peace.
Let's wait and see.
Are you okay?
Zeqiu,
I want to talk to you about something.
Can you...
No.
I'm trying to say—can you
go to school with me tomorrow?
Did I tell you that at school,
you're not allowed to mention
that you're my sister?
You did, but...
Since you're not my sister,
how can I accompany you to school?
It will cause misunderstandings.
Just for tomorrow, please?
Just one day.
Did something happen?
No.
Nothing.
Keep a distance of 10 meters.
What?
I mean,
when we go to school together tomorrow,
keep a distance of 10 meters.
Don't talk to me,
and no eye contact.
Don't let others misunderstand.
And when we enter the door later,
you only enter when I say so.
Okay.
Good night, Zeqiu.
Good night.
Two more minutes.
If time is up
and your team isn't all here,
you can't participate.
[Nanhai Province Star of Hope Math Contest
Preliminary Round]
Where is Jiang Yubai?
I don't know either.
[Nanhai Province Star of Hope Math Contest
Preliminary Round]
I'm here!
[Nanhai Province Star of Hope Math Contest
Preliminary Round]
Sit down.
[Nanhai Province Star of Hope Math Contest
Preliminary Round]
The test is out of 100 points.
You have 120 minutes.
You may begin now.
[Nanhai Province Star of Hope Math Contest
Preliminary Round]
Lin Zhixia,
that multiple-choice question,
the last one,
where xy > 0
and x+y = 1,
do you remember?
Is the answer C?
A.
By introducing auxiliary variables through
variable relationship transformations
and then applying
the Cauchy-Schwarz inequality,
the minimum value
can be solved as 1/3.
We talked about a similar question
in the library the day before yesterday.
I'm doomed.
I saw you sleep for 15 minutes
in the second half.
You completed it so quickly this time.
Speed doesn't matter.
The last question
was obviously out of my league.
If you ask a dog
to answer a Chinese test question,
could it answer it?
That's how I felt.
You seem quite proud of it.
I might not get first place,
but I definitely won't drag our team down.
I told you that you shouldn't have
chosen me as a teammate.
Ms. Last In Class.
How did you do this time?
It's none of your business.
Ignore him.
Let's go. Let's find a place
to help you estimate your score.
The library?
The library again?
I'm hungry.
We can eat first.
Let's go.
Lin Zhixia.
Don't worry.
Your team will definitely make it.
I'll compete with you in the finals.
Rest assured.
This time,
I'll let you know me more completely.
I'm doomed.
I can't even remember if I wrote my name.
Even if I did,
I definitely did terribly on this test.
I might not even pass.
Why did you lose confidence too?
I just talked big to Jiang Yubai.
If we don't make it to the finals,
won't it be super awkward?
What did you just say to him?
"I'll let you know me more completely."
I think
it was even more arrogant than that.
I also told him before
that until the finals are over,
I'd unfriend him
for this to be a pure competition.
You really hyped it up.
Sorry, sorry.
It's all my fault.
This is so embarrassing.
Anyway, the exam is over.
Whether we make it or not,
the result can't be changed.
Let's just have a happy dinner tonight.
Don't overthink it.
My treat.
Screwing up the exam,
even the skewers don't taste good anymore.
Who said you screwed up the exam?
You can't keep giving yourself
this kind of psychological suggestion.
Do you know the Law of Attraction?
What's that?
It's a psychological effect.
If you always think about bad things,
your life will be full of crises.
If you always focus on the good things,
you'll attract good results.
How?
Your thoughts and emotions
emit a frequency.
This frequency
can attract things
with the same frequency in the universe.
So you have to
place an order with the universe.
That sounds amazing.
All right, let's place an order now.
[Three-Two Kitchen]
Come on.
We will definitely
do very well in the exam this time,
and we will definitely advance.
We will definitely
do very well in the exam this time,
and we will definitely advance.
[Three-Two Kitchen]
Tang Tingting definitely
wrote her name on the test paper.
Then I hope my two friends
won't be so depressed tonight,
and we can have a happy meal together.
It seems to really work.
I feel quite happy now.
[Three-Two Kitchen]
Do you guys feel
like we used to be just teammates,
but now we're more like good friends?
Actually, in a way,
teammates have a deeper bond than friends.
After all, we have to experience success,
failure, joy, and sorrow together.
Working together
forces you to adapt to each other
and understand each other.
In difficult times,
we will understand and trust each other.
So since we are teammates,
we are naturally friends.
Let's make a toast.
We will definitely
do very well in the exam this time,
and we will definitely advance.
Definitely!
Cheers!
[Three-Two Kitchen]
[School notice board]
Lin Zhixia, look for it quickly.
I don't dare to look.
[Announcement of the Finalists]
Let's go.
What's wrong? Did we not make it?
We made it.
Fourth place.
Who is first?
A team from the experimental school.
They won because of their average score.
What about Jiang Yubai's team?
You're thinking about us?
We are not that talented—
just the runner-up in the preliminaries.
Congratulations.
You've taken the lead.
Although our team is ranked a bit higher,
you are the only one
with a perfect score in the preliminaries.
There are still finals.
Yeah.
There are finals.
Let's go.
We really made it to the finals.
We really made it.
Why am I smiling?
Happy for her?
Mocking.
I must be mocking her.
Lin Zhixia,
don't think I'm scared
just because someone got your back.
Tell that kid Jiang Yubai
not to be too arrogant.
I will get back at him
sooner or later.
[A New Chapter, A New Journey]
[Weiming Gymnasium]
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest] [Finals]
What should I do? I'm so nervous.
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest] [Finals]
What if I drag down
your average score again?
The finals have a different format.
It's not just
about individual performance.
As long as we cooperate well,
we'll be fine.
What if...
I'm here, don't worry.
Tingting.
Why is my mom here?
Mom, why are you here?
The other students' parents aren't here.
I don't care about others.
I have to come
to my daughter's competition.
Good luck.
Do your best.
All right, go up and have a seat.
Don't get distracted.
I believe in you.
Good luck.
Good luck!
My mom is seriously...
Your mom came to cheer for you.
Ma'am.
Good girl, you're here.
Cheer for her.
Go! She will win!
Why are there parents here?
They didn't ask parents to come, did they?
Come on.
The experimental school team,
who came first in the preliminaries,
is quite strong this year.
I don't know if we have a chance.
Probably?
They say there's
a really amazing student in Grade 10.
She was the top scorer
in the city's high school entrance exam.
I know. It's that girl.
Lin Zhixia, right?
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest] [Finals]
No way. Her team's preliminary performance
was average.
They only came 4th.
I don't have high hopes
for her with this format.
Why do you two have so much to say?
Which class are you from?
Ma'am.
Please turn off the flash.
Just 2 more pictures.
Please rise.
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest] [Finals]
Let's welcome the judges
[Host]
with our warmest applause.
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest] [Finals]
Please take a seat.
Next, I will read the rules
of the competition.
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest rules]
The competition lasts about 300 minutes
and consists of 3 rounds
with increasing difficulty,
testing the mathematical literacy
and teamwork of the contestants.
[Host]
The 1st round is compulsory.
The 3 members of each team, A, B, and C,
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest rules]
will take turns to answer.
Ten points will be added
for a correct answer,
and no points will be deducted
for a wrong one.
The 2nd round is a buzzer round.
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest rules]
Eight teams will compete for 10 questions.
5 points will be added
for a correct answer,
and 5 points will be deducted
for a wrong one.
The 3rd round
is a 60-minute group modeling.
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest rules]
Each team will complete
a comprehensive question
with 3 sub-questions.
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest] [Finals]
The score is 30 points.
Now, the competition begins.
[Host]
Don't be nervous. You can do it.
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest]
[Host]
[Nanhai No.1 High School Team 2,
10 points]
[Nanhai No.1 High School Team 4,
[Nanhai No.1 High School Team 2,
30 points]
[Nanhai No.1 High School Team 4,
20 points]
[Nanhai No.1 High School Team 2,
50 points]
[Host]
Next,
Contestant No. 3 from Team 4.
Given that parabola C:
y^2 = 4x
has two distinct points A and B
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest]
(A != B)
that are symmetric
with respect to the line l:
y = x + b,
find the range of values
for the real number b.
Please answer.
Why is her question so difficult?
b > -3.
The answer is wrong.
The correct answer is b < -3.
This question is too difficult.
No one could've answered it.
Yeah.
You can't make mistakes
at such a crucial moment.
[Tang Tingting] [Wrong answer]
It's fine.
This question is hard.
We still have the buzzer round.
Now it's the buzzer round.
You can press the buzzer
after the question is read,
but each team only has 1 chance.
Five points will be added
for a correct answer,
and 5 points will be deducted
for a wrong one.
The remaining teams
can continue to buzz in
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest]
until the correct answer is given,
or all teams have used their chances.
Question one.
Two people take turns rolling dice.
Each person rolls 2 dice at a time.
The first to get a sum
greater than 6 wins.
Otherwise, the other person rolls.
What is the winning probability
of the first roller?
Please answer.
Player 1 from team 4.
12/17.
That is correct.
Wow.
That's amazing.
Question two.
Find the range of the function f(x)
which equals squareroot (x - 5)
minutes the squareroot of (24 - 3x).
Please answer.
Player 1 from team 4 again.
Please pay attention
to the time left for answering.
There are 5 seconds left.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
Negative 3 to the square root of 3.
That is correct.
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest]
Lin Zhixia is so amazing.
She didn't even use scratch paper.
She calculated the answer mentally.
My goodness, that's impressive.
How can we compete with that?
There's no way.
Points are deducted for wrong answers.
So before buzzing in,
everyone must be absolutely sure.
But Lin Zhixia doesn't have this concern.
She always buzzes in first,
and calculates after getting the chance.
She's that confident?
Isn't she worried at all
that there might be
a question she can't solve?
No.
We're at a huge disadvantage
if this continues.
If we fall behind in the buzzer round,
we will be very passive later on.
We need to figure something out.
Question 3.
In a 3x3 grid,
going from the top left corner
to the bottom right corner,
you can only move right or down each time.
Find—
Player 1 from team 2, are you sure
you want to answer before the question
is finished?
The question isn't even finished.
That's too hasty.
Yes.
Okay, please answer.
This question
should be asking for the shortest path.
It's 6.
There are 6 different shortest paths.
Team 2's answer...
is correct.
Yes!
Not bad, you've learned
to predict the question.
It's the only way to beat her
to the buzzer.
The following questions
won't be this easy.
If they dare to buzz in like that again,
they'll just lose points.
The difficulty should be increasing
from now on.
Even Lin Zhixia
won't be able
to rely solely on mental math.
We can't let our guard down.
Given that the function y equals a times
cosine squared x minus 3,
times sine x, its minimum value is
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest]
[Nanhai Province Star of Hope
Math Contest] [Correct answer]
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest]
All right,
this is the last buzzer question.
The number of positive integer solutions
to the equation x+y+z=2010,
satisfying x is less than or equal to y,
which is less than or equal to z, is?
Contestant 2 of Team 2, please answer.
The answer is 336843.
Incorrect.
You may now buzz in again.
Contestant 1 of Team 4,
what is your answer?
336675.
Correct.
[Nanhai Province
Star of Hope Math Contest]
[1st Place:
Nanhai No.1 High School, Team 4]
Next, I will announce
the modeling question.
[2nd Place:
Nanhai No.1 High School, Team 2]
In major sports events,
if an athlete successfully breaks
a world record,
the organizing committee
usually pays a hefty bonus.
A certain event set up
a record-breaking bonus of 25,000 euros.
The organizing committee
usually chooses to buy insurance...
Tang.
You really impressed me today.
For your level,
your performance was absolutely perfect.
You were just unlucky.
The questions you got wrong
were extremely difficult.
No one could have answered them.
Besides.
The next question
is a teamwork question.
Your team is currently in the lead,
and you have the strongest teammate
backing you up.
We are the ones who should be worried,
not you.
Duan Qiyan.
You're not the one who got it wrong.
I'm in a really bad mood right now.
Leave me alone.
Start working on
the reassigned tasks.
How about
we find Tang Tingting first?
Let her take a break to adjust.
She can join us when she feels better.
She is emotionally unstable right now,
so she's prone
to making mistakes in a rush.
If we want to win 1st place,
we have no margin for error.
Let's do as you say.
[Women]
Ms. Last In Class.
You have the worst score
in the whole competition.
[Women]
You have nothing to lose,
so why not give it your all?
This isn't just about winning or losing.
It's for the 2 teammates
who have always trusted you.
They have never given up on you.
Nor have they ever
treated you as just a benchwarmer.
Instead, they did everything they could,
trying their best to help you
improve your skills.
I'm here.
Don't worry.
Since we are teammates,
we are naturally friends too.
We will definitely
do very well in the exam this time,
and we will definitely advance.
Definitely.
Cheers.
It's also for your mother.
I know.
You must feel embarrassed
because in the whole arena,
only your parent came,
and you even answered
the question wrongly.
But do you know what I saw?
I saw that in your mum's eyes,
she thinks you're a great daughter—
one that's able to stand in
the provincial Math Olympiad arena.
There's no one else in her eyes.
She was using a camera
to record highlights of moments
exclusively yours the whole time.
Of course.
This is also fighting for yourself.
Although I usually
call you Ms. Last In Class
and tease you from time to time,
I've really been admiring you lately.
Lin Zhixia's special training,
that's something I can't take,
yet you persevered.
The effort and hardship
you put into the competition,
only you know best in your heart.
You have been constantly
breaking through yourself.
Don't you want to see
where your limit really is?
[Women]
Lin Zhixia.
I think for the last modeling question,
we can use Markov chains
and binomial
and Poisson distribution models, right?
I think this kind of question
is most suitable to use probability rules
as a modeling method.
I have an idea.
How about using Bayesian methods?
I'm fine with anything.
Jiang, what do you think?
Our team has
the best average foundational ability.
Our advantage is in the front end,
that is, the establishment of the model
and the parameter estimation stage.
So Markov chains
and the binomial
and Poisson distribution methods
are the most secure for us.
This model is classic
and highly applicable.
Other groups are highly likely
to choose this problem-solving approach.
Then what everyone is competing on
is computational complexity.
Our group has no absolute advantage.
If Team 4 also chooses the same method,
with Tang Tingting's personal ability
and her condition today,
she will definitely not be as good as us
in terms of details and rigor.
So I think
Lin Zhixia won't choose this.
She is too confident
in her personal abilities.
So she is very likely to choose
a modeling method
that emphasizes her personal thinking.
Such as grey models
and Grey Relation Analysis.
To widen the gap with other groups,
I think it is more appropriate
to use grey models
and Grey Relation Analysis now.
It can show strategic insights
that probability models cannot provide,
and can still work
when data is scarce.
This method is more flexible and agile.
But even if it's completed
by Lin Zhixia alone,
it won't affect
their team's final presentation.
What if the result is better?
No.
Although she has a deep understanding
of mathematical principles,
she will definitely forget the fact
that this is a team competition.
But in this way,
it relies on
your personal systems thinking
and interpretation ability.
Is there anything else I can do?
Leave it to me, don't worry.
There won't be any problems.
Frankly speaking,
the theoretical model
of Team 4 is very perfect,
but there are 2 problems.
First,
[Judge]
the assumptions
in the modeling process are not perfect.
Of course,
the final result won't be affected,
but it misses the scoring point.
But if you
analyze the above factors
using binomial
and Poisson distributions here,
[Judges]
wouldn't it be better?
In addition, grey models
is actually a prediction model
built by fitting
the original data
with an exponential function.
When the data doesn't
have good smoothness,
it will produce certain errors.
So this
is very obviously
a complete model thought up by one person.
Which one of you is it?
What this question tests
is not entirely about right or wrong,
[Judges]
but more importantly, teamwork.
A beautiful theory,
combined with perfect data insight,
can get a full score.
I will award this contest's MVP
to this student.
Her model is impeccable.
However,
just looking at the focal point
of the last question,
I think Team 2's plan
is more balanced.
So I want to give Team 2 full marks.
Team 4...
[Judges]
It's 20 points.
[1st Place,
Nanhai No. 1 High School Team 2]
Congratulations to Team 2
for winning the contest.
We won!
Did we win?
-We're the champions!
-Quick!
We won.
[1st Place,
Nanhai No. 1 High School Team 2]
[2nd Place,
Nanhai No. 1 High School Team 4]
You're back.
Just in time.
Wash your hands and let's eat.
I'm not hungry, I won't eat.
This is so sumptuous.
Come on.
It's all your favorite.
Medium rare.
Double cheese.
Hurry, while it's hot.
Whenever we eat Western food,
I always think of
how you looked when you were little.
So cute.
Do you remember
the first time you ate Western food?
You said to me, "Mom,
this is the most delicious thing
in the world."
Yang from my workplace
insisted on buying you snacks.
When he asked what you liked,
you told him you liked Western food.
You wanted T-bone steak,
Nasi Goreng, and borscht.
You completely confused him.
In the end,
he bought you to Western food.
Look at me!
Your dad
insisted we call him before eating.
He said you haven't called him for days,
and he misses you.
Mom.
Why don't you mention the competition?
Isn't it more obvious
when you deliberately avoid it?
I... I didn't.
I know.
You don't mention it
because you're afraid I'll be sad.
I didn't get
a single question right today.
I embarrassed you again, right?
You might as well just
scold me directly like before.
Let's not talk about this for now.
We are eating.
-Fine. I apologize.
-Let’s eat first.
I'm sorry.
I know that by participating
in this math contest,
I was just humiliating myself.
I didn't want to go in the first place.
You forced me to go.
Have you given up now?
Seeing your daughter is the dumbest one
and the worst one
among so many people—
the one who always embarrasses you
and isn't good enough—
are you happy now?
Tingting.
Tingting. Hey...
Waiter!
Pack this up.
Thank you. Please hurry.
What's wrong with your sister?
The provincial math contest.
She didn't get 1st place.
That's it?
That scared me.
Let's not talk about the contest today.
If she doesn't want to eat,
let her be alone for a while.
Okay.
Then go wash your hands and come eat.
I thought
being one step ahead
could shield you from all the storms.
Until my shadow
completely blocked your light.
I'm sorry.
This apology
cannot compare
to the height of your stacked drafts.
My self-righteousness
so easily shattered
everyone's hard work.
I don't deserve us.
And I definitely don't deserve first place.